Guide to the Hervey DeWitt Griswold papers, 1897-1959.
Griswold, Hervey Dewitt papers, 1897-1959.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hervey DeWitt Griswold papers, 1897-1959.
2124
Hervey DeWitt Griswold, 1860-1945.
.2 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, pamphlets, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dr. Griswold's "Autobiographical Notes, prepared for his descendants" (247 pp., 1938-40); two printed copies of Griswold's studies of Hinduism; five typed or printed items pertaining to his career as a missionary at Forman Christian College, Lahore, India (now Pakistan); pamphlet "Sketches of My Indian Childhood" by Frances Griswold Wooddell (116 pp., n.d.); genealogical pamphlet on the Griswold family of Dryden, New York; and typescript poems by Hervey De Witt Griswold (28 pp.).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Missionary, professor of philosophy, Presbyterian minister.
Hervey DeWitt Griswold received his Ph.D. from Cornell in 1900.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Dr. Griswold's "Autobiographical Notes, prepared for his descendants" (247 pp., 1938-40); two printed copies of Griswold's studies of Hinduism; five typed or printed items pertaining to his career as a missionary at Forman Christian College, Lahore, India (now Pakistan); pamphlet "Sketches of My Indian Childhood" by Frances Griswold Wooddell (116 pp., n.d.); genealogical pamphlet on the Griswold family of Dryden, New York; and typescript poems by Hervey De Witt Griswold (28 pp.).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Griswold, Hervey DeWitt, 1860-1945.; Wooddell, Frances Griswold, 1900-; Forman Christian College.
Subjects:
Hinduism.; Missions--Pakistan--Lahore.; Presbyterians--Missions.; Missionaries.
Places:
Lahore (Pakistan)--Religious life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Autobiographies.; Genealogies.; Poems.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Manuscript: "Autobiographical Notes, prepared for his descendants," written by Dr. Griswold between Aug. 1938 and Apr. 1940 [see pp. 1, 246]. 247 pp., written on lined loose-leaf notebook paper. Chapter contents as follows: (Box 1)
  I. "Early Days and First School," pp. 1-7.
  II. "The Dryden School and Youthful Poetry," pp. 7-36.
  III. "Miscellaneous Experiences at High School," pp. 36-48.
  IV. "Union College 1881-1883," pp. 49-59.
  V. "First Term, Junior Year," pp. 55-99.
  VI. "Second Term, Junior Year," pp. 99-129.
  VII. "Third Term, Junior Year," pp. 129-154.
  VIII. "Fourth Year, Union College," pp. 154-163.
  IX. "Union Theological Seminary," 1885-1888, pp. 163-169.
  X. "Oxford and Berlin," [1888-1889, 1889-1890], pp. 169-179.
  XI. "In India, 1891," pp. 179-247. [Actually includes entire career in India; work for Ph.D. at Cornell, 1899-1900; family; travels in Europe and Near East; people met, etc.]
- Printed items
  - Bound into one volume: "The Dayanandi Interpretation of the Word 'Deva' in the Rig Veda," Lodiana: Mission Press, 1897, 23 pp. and Cornell Studies in Philosophy No. 2 - "Brahman: A Study in the History of Indian Philosophy," New York: Macmillan, 1900, 89 pp. Both by Dr. Griswold. [Cover in poor condition.] (Box 1)
  - Typescript excerpts from an article in "The Continent," Jan. 15, 1925, by Cleland B. McAfee, "Griswold of India." 3 pp. (Box 1)
  - Typescript copy of editorial in praise of Dr. Griswold appearing in the Forman Christian College magazine, Jan. 1928. (Box 1)
  - Advertisement for a scholarly publication, The Moslem World, showing table of contents page for the Jan. 1913 issue, published in London in the interests of Christian missions in Moslem lands. (Box 1)
  - "The Ancestors and Descendants of Edward Griswold of Dryden, New York," compiled by Hervey DeWitt Griswold and Minnie Griswold Space, 1930. 82 pp. (Box 1)
  - Seventy-fifth Anniversary Series, "India Awakening," by Rev. H.D. Griswold, D.D., published by The Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A., N.Y.C., Apr. 1912. 12 pp. (Box 1)
  - "The Folio," the Forman Christian College magazine, May-June 1942. Published by E.T. Dean, Forman Christian College, Lahore. 40 pp. in English, remainder in Urdu, Hindi, and Panjabi. (Box 1)
  - "Founders' Day, 1959. Address delivered by Dr. F.M. Velte in the College Hall on Mar. 3, 1959," printed in the Forman Christian College Founders' day pamphlet published by the Northern Pakistan Printing & Publishing Company, Lahore, 1959. 12 pp. (Box 1)
  - Typescript copy of poems by Hervey DeWitt Griswold, 28 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Sketches of My Indian Childhood," n.d. 116 pp. pamphlet. (Box 1)
- Monographs
  - The God Varuna in the Rig-Veda, Bulletin No. 1 of the Society of Comparative Theology and Philosophy. A Paper Read before the Society ..., Cornell University, Jan. 22, 1910. (Taylor & Carpenter: Ithaca, N.Y., Apr. 12, 1910 ). 36 pp. (Box 1)
  - The Love of God, A Sermon Preached in Kellogg Memorial Church, Landour, on Aug. 4th, 1907, and published by request. (The 'Albert' Press: Labhore, 1907 ). 6 pp. (Box 1)
  - Methods of Teaching Village Christians to Read, (Christian Literature Society for India: Madras, 1915 ). 56 pp. (Box 1)
  - Sermons, (Kellogg Memorial Church: Landour, 1925 ). 39 pp. (Box 1)